Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and today we're talking about helping other people.
我是Catherine，今天我们讨论的是帮助他人。
That's right.
没错。
We are going to volunteer and to help other people that maybe don't have as much as we
我们要去做志愿者，帮助那些可能不如我们拥有得多的人，
do and so this is a way to give back to the community.
这是一种回馈社区的方式。
That's right.
没错。
So this is an intermediate level lesson and before we get going, we have a phrase to preview
这是一个中级课程，在开始之前，我们先预览一个短语，
in today's vocabulary preview.
在今天的词汇预览中。
Vocabulary preview.
词汇预览。
All right.
好的。
So in vocabulary preview today, we have this phrase, a soup kitchen or it's a noun, a soup
在今天的词汇预览中，我们有这个短语，a soup kitchen，它是一个名词，
kitchen.
soup kitchen。
That's right.
没错。
A soup kitchen is a place.
Soup kitchen是一个地方。
Basically, it is a place where volunteers can help cook and serve people who don't have
基本上，它是一个志愿者可以帮忙做饭和提供服务的地方，给那些没有
enough money to feed themselves.
足够钱养活自己的人。
Okay.
好的。
So that's a soup kitchen.
这就是soup kitchen。
It's basically a place where people can get free food.
基本上是一个人们可以免费获得食物的地方。
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
So this is where we're going to be today.
所以这就是我们今天要去的地方。
We are at a soup kitchen and we're going to hear a couple of people talking about helping
我们在一个soup kitchen，会听到几个人谈论在soup kitchen帮忙
out at a soup kitchen.
的事情。
Let's listen.
我们来听一下。
Thanks a lot for pitching in once again, Judy.
非常感谢你又一次来帮忙，Judy。
We really appreciate your help.
我们真的很感激你的帮助。
It seems that at this time of year, there are more and more people who are struggling
似乎每年这个时候，有越来越多的人都在艰难地
to make ends meet.
维持生计。
There aren't many professional chefs like you who are so generous with their time.
像你这样慷慨奉献时间的专业厨师并不多。
Don't be silly, Mark.
别这么说，Mark。
I'm more than happy to devote my time to a good cause.
我非常乐意把我的时间奉献给一个好事业。
Volunteering at the soup kitchen has been really rewarding for me.
在soup kitchen做志愿者对我来说真的很有意义。
You know, it's satisfying to provide good meals for those who are less fortunate.
你知道，为那些不幸的人提供好饭菜是很有满足感的。
I feel like I'm really making a difference in some small way.
我觉得我在某种程度上真的在做出改变。
Well, your skills are definitely appreciated here.
嗯，你的技能在这里绝对受到赞赏。
The people who come here have fallen on hard times and a delicious hot meal can really
来这里的人都经历了困难时期，一顿美味的热饭真的能
bolster their spirits.
提振他们的精神。
Wow, that smells great.
哇，闻起来真香。
The needy are sure lucky to have you.
有需要的人有你真是幸运。
Thanks Mark.
谢谢，Mark。
Here you go.
给你。
Enjoy your meal.
请享用你的餐。
Thank you, my dear.
谢谢你，亲爱的。
Oh, this looks lovely.
哦，这看起来真不错。
You're welcome.
不客气。
Hello, sir.
你好，先生。
Today we have George.
今天我们有George。
What are you doing here?
你在这里干什么？
Hey, Judy.
嘿，Judy。
I'll have a little of everything.
我每样都来一点。
Thanks.
谢谢。
Mmm, smells great.
嗯，闻起来真香。
George, seriously, what are you doing here?
George，说真的，你在这里干什么？
I haven't seen you since our divorce was finalized.
自从我们离婚手续办完后，我就没见过你。
You've got no right to be here.
你没权利来这里。
You're hardly homeless.
你根本不是无家可归的人。
Don't be like that, Judy.
别这样，Judy。
I really miss your home cooking.
我真的很想念你做的家常菜。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So obviously this person, what was he, George, he didn't really need the food, but apparently
所以很明显这个人，他叫什么，George，他并不真的需要食物，但显然
I think he's divorced from his wife and he was like, oh, I need your food.
我觉得他和妻子离婚了，他就像在说，哦，我需要你的食物。
But other people that were there were very much in need of this food.
但其他在那里的人确实非常需要这些食物。
So why don't we take a look at some of the words and phrases on Language Takeaway.
所以我们来看看语言要点中的一些单词和短语。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
Well, we've got a couple of interesting words here at the beginning that have to do with
嗯，我们开头有几个有趣的词，和
volunteering or helping other people.
做志愿者或帮助他人有关。
The first phrase we have actually is to pitch in.
我们第一个短语实际上是to pitch in。
That's right, to pitch in.
没错，to pitch in。
So when you pitch in, that's a way of saying helping, right?
所以当你pitch in时，这是一种表示帮助的方式，对吧？
That's right, to help.
没错，就是帮助。
So I could ask you for your help with something.
所以我可以请你帮忙做某事。
I could say, hey, Marco, can you pitch in a little of your time with this project I
我可以说，嘿，Marco，你能为我的这个项目抽出一点时间吗？
have?
Okay, so dedicate or to help, to pitch in.
好的，所以是奉献或帮助，to pitch in。
So when you pitch in, you are helping.
所以当你pitch in时，你就是在帮忙。
This is a really common phrase, very colloquial though, right?
这是一个非常常见的短语，但很口语化，对吧？
To pitch in, that's right.
To pitch in，没错。
Okay.
好的。
And then moving on, another adjective.
接下来，另一个形容词。
When a person likes to help or gives money to the poor, that person is generous.
当一个人喜欢帮助别人或捐钱给穷人时，这个人就是慷慨的。
That's right.
没错。
So generous is an adjective.
所以“generous”是一个形容词。
It means a person can be generous or an effort can be generous.
它意味着一个人可以是慷慨的，或者一种努力可以是慷慨的。
For example, a very famous generous person is Mother Teresa of Calcutta.
例如，一个非常著名的慷慨之人是加尔各答的特蕾莎修女。
I was thinking Warren Buffett, but both of them are very generous.
我想到的是沃伦·巴菲特，但他们俩都非常慷慨。
Mother Teresa for giving back to the poor and Warren Buffett for donating most of his
特蕾莎修女回馈穷人，而沃伦·巴菲特捐出了他大部分
money.
财富。
Okay, very good.
好的，非常好。
So that is a sign of a person that is generous.
所以这就是一个慷慨之人的标志。
So usually generous people like Warren Buffett, you say he gave away his fortune to people
通常像沃伦·巴菲特这样慷慨的人，你会说他把自己的财富捐给了那些
that didn't have money.
没有钱的人。
We call these people the less fortunate.
我们称这些人为“不幸的人”。
That's right.
没错。
So as you said, we've got three words here that mean poor people basically.
所以正如你所说，我们这里有三个词基本上都指穷人。
And we don't like to say poor people in English because it's not very nice.
在英语中我们不喜欢说“穷人”，因为这不太礼貌。
You know, people can't control their situation in many cases and it's more of a situation
你知道，很多情况下人们无法控制自己的处境，这更多是一种
of not having what others have.
缺乏他人所拥有的东西的状态。
And so one way to say this is less fortunate.
所以一种说法是“less fortunate”。
So a person that's less fortunate is a person that's poor.
所以“less fortunate”的人就是穷人。
That's right.
没错。
So for example, we often try to help the less fortunate by volunteering our time.
例如，我们经常通过志愿奉献时间来帮助那些不幸的人。
Okay, so fortunate is a way of saying that you have fortune or you have luck.
好的，“fortunate”是一种说法，表示你有福气或运气。
So if you say you are very fortunate, that means that you are very lucky.
所以如果你说你很“fortunate”，那就意味着你非常幸运。
That's right.
没错。
Okay, so less fortunate means poor.
好的，所以“less fortunate”意味着贫穷。
And another way of saying that somebody is poor, you say that person is needy.
另一种说某人贫穷的方式是，你说那个人是“needy”。
Needy.
“Needy”。
So this probably makes you think of the word need to need and you're right.
这可能会让你想到“need”这个词，你说得对。
This comes from need.
它来源于“need”。
So someone who is needy needs things, needs money, needs help, needs food.
所以一个“needy”的人需要东西，需要钱，需要帮助，需要食物。
Okay, even attention, right?
好的，甚至需要关注，对吧？
Somebody that's needy might need a lot of attention all the time.
一个“needy”的人可能总是需要很多关注。
That's right.
没错。
So this could actually be a bad thing.
所以这实际上可能是一件坏事。
Someone who's needy says, look at me, look at me.
一个“needy”的人会说：“看我，看我。”
Oh my gosh, look at me, listen to me.
哦天哪，看我，听我说。
And that can be very annoying.
那可能非常烦人。
Okay, so the needy.
好的，所以“the needy”。
And now finally, a very common word to say that somebody is very poor, doesn't have a
现在最后，一个非常常见的词来形容某人非常贫穷，没有
place to live, doesn't have a home.
地方住，没有家。
You say that person is homeless.
你说那个人是“homeless”。
Homeless literally means without a home.
“Homeless”字面意思就是无家可归。
And so we often talk about the homeless as being a group of people we want to help in
所以我们经常谈论“the homeless”作为社会中我们想要帮助的一群人，
society because the homeless live on the streets, they live in public and in the winter and
因为无家可归者住在街上，住在公共场所，在冬天和
times when it's really, really cold, it's very dangerous for them.
非常寒冷的时候，这对他们来说非常危险。
So the homeless are a group that people try to help with these soup kitchens and shelters.
所以无家可归者是一群人们试图通过施粥所和收容所来帮助的人。
Okay, very good.
好的，非常好。
So a lot of interesting words, common phrases, they're very useful.
所以有很多有趣的词汇，常用短语，它们非常有用。
So why don't we go back, listen to this dialogue again and we'll be back in a little bit with
那么我们为什么不回去，再听一遍这段对话，稍后我们会回来进行
Fluency Builder.
流利度训练。
Thanks a lot for pitching in once again, Judy.
非常感谢你再次帮忙，朱迪。
We really appreciate your help.
我们真的很感激你的帮助。
It seems that at this time of year, there are more and more people who are struggling
似乎每年这个时候，有越来越多的人
to make ends meet.
难以维持生计。
There aren't many professional chefs like you who are so generous with their time.
没有多少像你这样专业的厨师如此慷慨地奉献时间。
Don't be silly, Mark.
别傻了，马克。
I'm more than happy to donate my time to a good cause.
我非常乐意为一个好的事业奉献我的时间。
Volunteering at the soup kitchen has been really rewarding for me.
在施粥所做志愿者对我来说真的很有意义。
You know, it's satisfying to provide good meals for those who are less fortunate.
你知道，为那些不幸的人提供美味的饭菜是令人满足的。
I feel like I'm really making a difference in some small way.
我觉得我确实在某种程度上有所贡献。
Well, your skills are definitely appreciated here.
嗯，你的技能在这里绝对受到赞赏。
The people who come here have fallen on hard times and a delicious hot meal can really
来这里的人们都陷入了困境，一顿美味的热饭真的能
bolster their spirits.
提振他们的精神。
Wow, that smells great.
哇，闻起来真香。
The needy are sure lucky to have you.
那些贫困的人有你真是幸运。
Thanks Mark.
谢谢，马克。
Here you go.
给你。
Enjoy your meal.
请享用你的餐点。
Thank you, my dear.
谢谢你，亲爱的。
Oh, this looks lovely.
哦，这看起来真不错。
You're welcome.
不客气。
Hello, sir.
你好，先生。
Today, we have George.
今天，我们有乔治。
What are you doing here?
你在这里做什么？
Hey, Judy.
嘿，朱迪。
I'll have a little of everything.
我每样都来一点。
Thanks.
谢谢。
Smells great.
闻起来真香。
George, seriously, what are you doing here?
乔治，说真的，你在这儿干什么？
I haven't seen you since our divorce was finalized.
自从我们离婚手续办完后，我就再没见过你。
You've got no right to be here.
你没权利待在这儿。
You're hardly homeless.
你又不是无家可归。
Don't worry, I'm not homeless.
别担心，我不是无家可归。
I'm just a little homeless.
我只是有点无家可归。
I'm not homeless.
我不是无家可归。
I'm a homeless person.
我是一个无家可归的人。
What are you doing here?
你在这儿干什么？
Mostly, the little house, actually.
主要是，其实是在那个小房子里。
Enjoy your meal.
请慢用。
There is no need to be here.
没必要待在这儿。
Yes, Joe.
是的，乔。
I'm Sergeant Hstock.
我是哈斯托克警长。
It's great to see you.
很高兴见到你。
What is this?
这是什么？
Don't be like that, Judy.
别这样，朱迪。
I really miss your home cooking.
我真的很想念你做的家常菜。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So, on Fluency Builder, today we have three key phrases.
那么，在流利度训练中，今天我们有三个关键短语。
So, we're gonna take a look at those now.
所以，我们现在来看看这些。
OK.
好的。
So, what is that first phrase?
那么，第一个短语是什么？
Our first phrase comes from the starting of the dialogue with Mark who says there are
我们的第一个短语来自对话的开头，马克说有一些
some people who are struggling to make ends meet.
人正在艰难地维持生计。
So, the phrase here is, to make ends meet.
所以，这里的短语是，维持生计。
OK.
好的。
Make ends meet.
维持生计。
So, if you take a look at this phrase, it's very hard to determine what that actually
所以，如果你看看这个短语，很难确定它实际上
means.
是什么意思。
What does it mean?
它是什么意思？
Think about a string.
想象一根绳子。
If you want to make a circle out of that string, you have to connect the ends.
如果你想用那根绳子做一个圈，你必须把两端连接起来。
I think of that as being about your income and the money that you spend.
我认为这指的是你的收入和花的钱。
I cannot make ends meet if I earn $10 every week but I spend $15 on my house and my food.
如果我每周赚10美元，但花15美元在房子和食物上，我就无法维持生计。
So, not being able to make ends meet means you spend more than you earn.
所以，无法维持生计意味着你花的比赚的多。
That's not about cars and fancy TVs.
这不是关于汽车和花哨的电视。
That's about your house, your heat, your bills, and your food.
这是关于你的房子、暖气、账单和食物。
But I say, I've been able to make ends meet for a while now because I have a pretty good
但我说，我最近一段时间能维持生计，因为我有一份相当好的
job.
工作。
So, to make ends meet is to be able to pay for your necessities.
所以，维持生计就是能够支付你的必需品。
But he can't make ends meet means he can't support himself financially.
但他无法维持生计意味着他无法在经济上养活自己。
Very good.
很好。
To make ends meet is pretty much to satisfy your basic necessities.
维持生计基本上就是满足你的基本必需品。
Financially.
在经济上。
Okay.
好的。
Very good.
很好。
And moving on, when we were talking about generosity and people helping out, if you
继续，当我们谈论慷慨和人们帮忙时，如果你
help people that are less fortunate, you are making a difference in a small way.
帮助那些不幸的人，你就在以小小的方式做出改变。
Okay.
好的。
So, this is a phrase that we hear all the time in the States.
所以，这是一个我们在美国经常听到的短语。
I'm not sure if it's the same in other English-speaking countries but it's a very popular phrase.
我不确定在其他英语国家是否也一样，但这是一个非常流行的短语。
We talk about making a difference or trying to make a difference and it's not very clear
我们谈论做出改变或试图做出改变，但不太清楚
what a difference really is.
改变到底是什么。
But generally this means doing good things for other people.
但通常这意味着为他人做好事。
Okay.
好的。
So, celebrities try to make a difference with their money and their fame.
所以，名人试图用他们的金钱和名声做出改变。
Some people try to make a difference by working at homeless shelters or at soup kitchens.
有些人通过在无家可归者收容所或施粥所做义工来做出改变。
And so, there are many different ways to make a difference.
所以，有很多不同的方式可以做出改变。
But it's basically the idea that you volunteer or you give money to help other people.
但这基本上是指你自愿或捐钱来帮助他人。
Okay.
好的。
Very good.
很好。
And if for example you recycle, you can say you're making a difference in the environment.
例如，如果你回收利用，你可以说你正在为环境做出改变。
That's right.
没错。
You're making a difference.
你在做出改变。
Usually a difference is a positive thing.
通常改变是积极的事情。
So, keep that in mind.
所以，记住这一点。
Very good.
很好。
And for the last phrase on Fluency Builder today, we say that people who come here have
至于今天流利度训练的最后一个短语，我们说来到这里的人
fallen on hard times.
陷入了困境。
So, people that have fallen on hard times.
所以，那些陷入困境的人。
What does it mean if you fall on hard times?
如果你陷入困境，这意味着什么？
Well, basically hard times are difficulties, right?
嗯，基本上“困境”就是困难，对吧？
So, not being able to make ends meet, not being able to pay for your food and your housing.
所以，就是入不敷出，无法支付食物和住房的费用。
And so, we have the verb to fall.
然后，我们有一个动词“fall”。
You've fallen on hard times because you've gone from a place where you're comfortable
你陷入了困境，因为你从舒适的地方
to a lower place, a place where life is really hard.
跌落到一个更低的地方，一个生活非常艰难的地方。
And so, think of this as a fixed phrase.
所以，把这看作一个固定短语。
He fell on hard times or they fell on hard times.
他陷入了困境，或者他们陷入了困境。
This means they don't have much money or they can't support themselves or they went bankrupt,
这意味着他们没多少钱，或者无法养活自己，或者破产了，
for example.
例如。
So, somebody that loses their job may have fallen on hard times.
所以，失业的人可能就陷入了困境。
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
And there's one more phrase here that deserves a little attention.
还有一个短语值得注意一下。
We heard this word to bolster.
我们听到了“bolster”这个词。
To bolster is a verb that means to improve.
“Bolster”是一个动词，意思是改善。
So, a hot meal can really bolster their spirits.
所以，一顿热饭真的能提振他们的精神。
It means it can make them feel better.
意思是能让他们感觉好一些。
So, to bolster their spirits means to make them feel happier, to lift their spirits.
所以，“提振他们的精神”意思是让他们更开心，振作精神。
That's right.
没错。
Exactly what you said, to make them feel happier.
正是你说的，让他们感觉更开心。
Okay.
好的。
Awesome.
太棒了。
So, a lot of interesting phrases there.
所以，这里有很多有趣的短语。
Phrases that you can talk in English about making a difference, about volunteering.
你可以用英语谈论产生影响、做志愿服务的短语。
Very interesting stuff.
非常有趣的内容。
Very good for conversations between friends and family.
非常适合朋友和家人之间的对话。
So, why don't we go back, listen to the dialogue again and we'll be back to talk a little bit
所以，我们为什么不回去，再听一遍对话，然后我们会回来再聊一点
more.
更多内容。
Thanks a lot for pitching in once again, Judy.
非常感谢你再次帮忙，朱迪。
We really appreciate your help.
我们真的很感激你的帮助。
It seems that at this time of year, there are more and more people who are struggling
似乎每年这个时候，越来越多的人都在挣扎着
to make ends meet.
维持生计。
There aren't many professional chefs like you who are so generous with their time.
像你这样慷慨奉献时间的专业厨师并不多。
Don't be silly, Mark.
别傻了，马克。
I'm more than happy to devote my time to a good cause.
我非常乐意把时间投入到一项好事上。
Volunteering at the Soup Kitchen has been really rewarding for me.
在施粥所做志愿者对我来说一直很有意义。
You know, it's satisfying to provide good meals for those who are less fortunate.
你知道，为那些不幸的人提供好饭菜让我很满足。
I feel like I'm really making a difference in some small way.
我觉得自己在某种程度上真的产生了影响。
Well, your skills are definitely appreciated here.
嗯，你的技能在这里绝对受到赞赏。
The people who come here have fallen on hard times and a delicious hot meal can really
来这里的人都陷入了困境，一顿美味的热饭真的能
bolster their spirits.
提振他们的精神。
Wow, that smells great.
哇，闻起来真香。
The needy are sure lucky to have you.
有你在，那些贫困的人真是幸运。
Thanks Mark.
谢谢，马克。
Here you go.
给你。
Enjoy your meal.
请享用你的饭菜。
Thank you, my dear.
谢谢你，亲爱的。
Oh, this looks lovely.
哦，这看起来真不错。
You're welcome.
不客气。
Hello, sir.
你好，先生。
Today we have George.
今天我们有乔治。
What are you doing here?
你在这里干什么？
Hey, Judy.
嘿，朱迪。
I'll have a little of everything, thanks.
我每样都来一点，谢谢。
Mmm, smells great.
嗯，闻起来真香。
George, seriously, what are you doing here?
乔治，说真的，你在这里干什么？
I haven't seen you since our divorce was finalized.
自从我们离婚最终确定后，我就没见过你。
You've got no right to be here.
你没权利来这里。
You're hardly homeless.
你根本不是无家可归。
Don't be like that, Judy.
别这样，朱迪。
I really miss your home cooking.
我真的很想念你做的家常菜。
Alright, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So talking about volunteering, have you ever done any volunteer work?
说到做志愿者，你做过志愿工作吗？
I have.
我做过。
I've done it a bit, actually.
实际上，我做过一些。
Yeah?
是吗？
What have you done?
你做过什么？
Back when I was living in the United States, in Chicago, I used to cook for a homeless shelter
以前我住在美国芝加哥的时候，我每周都会为一家无家可归者收容所
every week.
做饭。
So I would bring food every Thursday.
所以每个星期四我都会带食物过去。
So you cook at home and you bring the food over to the shelter?
所以你在家做饭，然后把食物送到收容所？
That's right.
没错。
So the shelter had a kitchen, but they used donations from people because there are so
收容所有厨房，但他们用人们的捐赠，因为有很多
many people who came there for food.
人来那里找食物。
And once a month I would volunteer to also serve the food.
每个月我会自愿去帮忙分一次食物。
So I would bring lasagna or pasta, things that most people like.
所以我会带千层面或意大利面，这些大多数人喜欢的东西。
And then once a month I would sit down with people and talk.
然后每个月我会坐下来和人们聊一次天。
You know, a lot of people are lonely when they're in homeless shelters because they
你知道，很多人在收容所里很孤独，因为他们
come alone or maybe it's the mother and her child.
是独自来的，或者可能是母亲带着孩子。
It's nice to also come and sit and talk to them.
能过来坐下来和他们聊聊天也挺好的。
No, it's very interesting and I think volunteering is a much better solution than, for example,
不，这非常有趣，而且我认为志愿服务比，比如说，
just giving out money to poor people or something like that.
直接给穷人钱或类似的事情要好得多。
I don't think that's really the solution.
我不认为那真的是解决办法。
I think you should dedicate your time and your energy to making a difference, like in
我认为你应该投入时间和精力去做出改变，就像
the dialogue.
对话里那样。
And I think that the other benefit is for you, the volunteer, because it changes your
而且我认为另一个好处是对你，志愿者本人，因为它会改变你
perspective on poverty and on humanity.
对贫困和人性的看法。
And you think about, well, you know, I could be this person.
你会想，嗯，你知道，我可能也会变成这个人。
He was a banker two years ago and now he doesn't have a house.
他两年前还是个银行家，现在却无家可归。
And so I think it has a positive effect on everybody involved.
所以我认为这对所有参与者都有积极的影响。
Yeah, for sure.
是的，当然。
No, I think it's a very rewarding experience.
不，我认为这是一次非常有意义的经历。
And I think EnglishPod definitely supports that you should volunteer, you should make
而且我认为EnglishPod绝对支持你应该做志愿者，你应该
a difference.
做出改变。
And I think we can all help each other, right?
而且我认为我们都可以互相帮助，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
Have you ever volunteered?
你做过志愿者吗？
What kind of volunteer work have you done?
你做过哪种志愿工作？
Has it been environmental or social?
是环保方面的还是社会方面的？
Let us know on our website, EnglishPod.com.
请在我们的网站EnglishPod.com上告诉我们。
We hope to see you there.
我们希望能在那里见到你。
All right.
好了。
Bye, everyone.
大家再见。
Thank you.
谢谢。